# **Dow Jones**

## Senior Software Engineer

Seattle, WA | google-email@gmail.com | LinkedIn

# **Work Experience**

#### Senior Software Engineer, Wix.com

Poland, September 2021 - May 2024

Launched a platform for integration with partners - payment providers from 160+ countries, organized the processing of transactions for the biggest world site builder, with payments, available to operate in 160+ countries

- Led an integration of Google Pay, opened this payment method to 2.5% of all websites worldwide, built on Wix
- Overhauled monitoring for the stability of a high-transaction platform, which brought the team to reduce the number of incidents by 20%+ each year
- Introduced the first Buy Now, Pay Later (BNPL) payment methods under Wix Payments (Wix payment provider)
- Implemented the SPI platform for 3rd-party partners which allows the creation of custom payment providers and integration with Wix

## Senior Software Engineer, Intapp

USA, April 2020 - September 2021

Led the migration of Intapp's flagship project, Integration Builder, from a desktop environment to a web application, in tight cooperation with the partner company, Dell

- Development of a microservice architecture (10+ services) for a new design
- Designed the authentication layer with other protective measures such as rate limiting, anomaly detection, load shredding

### Full Stack Software Engineer, Capveriant

Germany, April 2019 - April 2020

Built a backend & frontend for the fintech B2B product for the German & French market

- Introduced the Event Sourcing design (CQRS) to the architecture, simplifying maintenance of the state with more than 20 possible statuses
- Integrated BI events, metrics & alerts to the system (~1k events/day)

#### **Backend Software Engineer, PST.AG**

Germany, November 2017 - April 2019

Development of web crawlers and search bot solutions tailored to the requirements of prominent companies, including those ranking among the top 20 companies in Germany

- Led the dockerization of the platform for data gathering (drastically increased the speed of deploying & running crawlers: 30-50%)
- Integration of the Apache NiFi into the platform, improving the simplicity and clearness of the data flows

#### **Skills**

Languages: Java, Scala, JS, TS, SQL, Rust

Technologies & Frameworks: Protocol Buffers, gRPC, Bazel, Angular, Spring, ReactJS, Blockchain, Kafka, Selenium,

HTML & CSS, REST API, Microservices, CI/CD, NoSQL, Docker, Kubernetes

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB

**Cloud services:** Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, Vultr **Others:** Grafana, Metrics, Alerting, New Relic, Git, Github Actions

# **Education**

• Master's degree in Computer Science

**September 2017 - June 2019** 

Donetsk National University

Master's degree in Mathematical Statistics

**September 2015 - June 2017** 

Donetsk National University

Bachelor's degree in Mathematical Statistics September 2011 - June 2015

Donetsk National University

#### **Summary**

A software engineer with a commitment to solving complex problems, Dow Jones possesses over 7 years of experience in backend development, architecture design, payments domain (platform with 10 million txs/month) and delivering software solutions for any business requirements to any domain.